Melinda Hardin

EDUCATION

University of Kansas, Coding Program, Full-stack Developer Graduate Certificate: 07/2018 Western Kentucky University, Organizational Leadership, Bachelor of Science: 05/2016 Sullivan University, Paralegal Studies, Associate of Science: 05/2006

SUMMARY

Full-stack developer. Experienced in MERN with use of MongoDB and MySQL. Thrive on collaboration and working with people of all backgrounds. Strong written and verbal communication skills. Currently expanding on knowledge of React and MongoDB.

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

HTML | CSS | JavaScript | Bootstrap | Nodejs | jQuery | Firebase | AJAX | JSON | APIs | Command Line | Git | Databases such as MySQL and MongoDB | Express | Node | Authentication | creating Servers

EXAMPLES OF WORK

Eat-da-Burger | github repository

Project Description: The user adds a burger which populates into the "to eat" column. The user then either clicks "yum" to eat the burger or "delete" to remove it from the table. If "yum" is clicked, the burger is then added to the "burgers eaten" column. **Technologies/Frameworks Used:** MySQL, Node, Express, Handlebars and Object-relational Mapping (ORM)

Click Game | github repository

Project Description: A React Application. The user clicks different images which listens for click events. The app keeps track of the users' score which is incremented when an image is clicked for the first time. If the image is clicked more than once, the score resets to 0 and the game restarts.

Technologies/Frameworks Used: Bootstrap, CSS, React and JavaScript

Freelance Web Developer Dates

- Designed, developed and maintain entertainment website. Built with React. Retrieves data stored in MongoDB.
- Created an inventory system which retrieves information from MySQL.
- Analyze user needs. Determine feasibility of design and time frame.
- Collaborate with county government IT department to communicate needs of agencies.
- Worked with servers, applications and databases.
- Created clean, well-documented APIs.
- Developed detailed wireframes.

Previous Work Experience

Johnson County	Paralegal	04/2016-Present
Office of Attorney General	Paralegal	02/2014-11/2015
Kahane & Associates	Paralegal/Trainer	11/2010-11/2013